Guide to the Montana Department of Social and Rehabilitative Services, Medicaid Services Division records 1988-1992
Montana Historical Society Research Center
Montana Department of Social and Rehabilitative Services, Medicaid Services Division records
1988-1992
Montana Historical Society, Research Center Archives Archives 225 N. Roberts PO Box 201201 Helena MT 59620-1201 (406) 444-2681 mhslibrary@mt.gov
RS 466
Montana. Department of Social and Rehabilitative Services.
.8 linear feet of shelf space
This collection is comprised of records of the Department of Social and Rehabilitative Services, Medicaid Services Division and contains subject files (1988-1992) primarily related to AIDS, Home Health, and Medicaid.
Administrative History
The Legislature established the Department of Public Welfare in 1937, consolidating state welfare activities. The Department was responsible for the administration of all forms of public assistance, including general relief programs and supervision of institutions caring for the dependent, delinquent, or mentally or physically handicapped. In 1971 the Department of Public Welfare was abolished and its functions assumed by the newly created Department of Social and Rehabilitation Services (SRS). The SRS assumed the functions of various state agencies, including functions pertaining to vocational rehabilitation and education; the Commission on Aging; and the Council on Human Resources. The SRS administered all forms of public assistance, child protection, and child welfare; gave consultant service to private institutions providing care for the needy, indigent, handicapped, or dependent; developed provisions for services to the blind; supervised county boards of public welfare; and administered all funds allotted for public welfare activities. State government reorganization in 1995 combined the SRS with portions of the Department of Health and Environmental Sciences to form the Department of Public Health and Human Services.
Content Description
This collection is composed of subject files (1988-1992) primarily related to AIDS, Home Health, and Medicaid.
This collection is arranged by series.
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
AIDS; Medicaid--Montana.
Montana
Medicine and Health
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Subject Files
  - AIDS, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 1 / 1-2)
  - AIDS, 1991 (Box-folder 1 / 3)
  - AIDS Five-Year Plan, 1992 (Box-folder 1 / 4)
  - AIDS – Harrington, Dee Capp, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 1 / 5)
  - AIDS – Information, 1991 (Box-folder 1 / 6)
  - AIDS – Regional Summit, 1989 (Box-folder 2 / 1)
  - AIDS – Request for Proposal, 1991 (Box-folder 2 / 2)
  - AIDS Task Force, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 2 / 3)
  - Automatic Certification Letters for Ceasarian-Delivery, 1988 (Box-folder 2 / 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 2 / 5-7)
  - Home Health Cost Analysis, 1990 (Box-folder 2 / 8)
  - Home Health Meeting, 1990 (Box-folder 2 / 9)
  - Home Health File #2, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 2 / 10)
  - Home Health – Specific Recipients, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 2 / 11)
  - Medicaid, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 2 / 12)
  - Medicaid Abuse Control, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 2 / 13)